

OMAR ALKOUR

software engineer

Address:
Dubai- UAE

Phone: +971585689943

Email: omar18pc@gmail.com

Birth-date: 18/6/1995

Gender: Male

Social status: Married.

LANGUAGES

Arabic – native language

English - Good

OVERVIEW

Determined software engineer, I work in web development using AngularJS Framework, PHP, and MySQL and have experience building desktop applications using C#, SQL, and IT Technical Support. Driven by my childhood obsession with technology, I have been studying and practicing software development and engineering for the past decade. I aspire to learn, gain new experience and improve my skills. I'm looking forward to putting my skills to use for a highly reputable organization such as yours.

EDUCATION

- Faculty of Informatics & Communication Engineering at Arab International University (AIU)
 - Bachelor degree class of 2021
 - o Specialized in Artificial Intelligence Science

EXPERIENCES

Web development

- Website Designing using ,PHP , CSS , HTML , javascript
- Designing e-commerce stores using wordpress
- Programming Web Applications Using Python
- Building databases for a website

3D Modeling for games

- creating virtual worlds and characters.
- Creating 3D characters for games.
- Animation 3D characters
- 3D modeling Programming and Programming games.
- interpreting concept arts and sketches, creating virtual characters, and props

artificial intelligence

- machine learning model using python
- Face Recognition

Arduino

- programming microcontroller (Arduino)
- Know all the sensors of the Arduino
- Utilizing Arduino in Machine Learning

Robot

- Knowledge in LEGO robot programming.
- Learn about building a LEGO robot.

Soft Skills

- Work well under pressure
- Flexible
- problem solving
- active listening
- Risk-Taking
- Welcome
 Collaboration

WORKS

Teaching the principles of robotics to kids, Alahlya National School

Jan 2021 - Apr 2021

Responsibilities:

- Teaching kids the principles of LEGO robots
- Teaching kids the basics of Arduino
- Teach children the basics of programming using program (scratch JR).

Web development, Freelance

Nov 2018 – Aug 2021

Responsibilities:

- Backend Design using PHP, MySQL, ASP.net
- Frontend using AngularJS
- Maintain and secure websites for clients.

apps development, Freelance

Nov 2018 - Aug 2021

Responsibilities:

- Application interface design
- Programming android applications for clients.

Games development, Freelance

Nov 2021 - Jan 2022

Responsibilities:

- Character graphics design.
- Programming games.
- Programming special physics for characters.

PERSONAL EXPERINCE

First aid Corse 2012

Nursing Corse in (Red Crescent) 2014

IT Technician, Titan Networks.

June 2014 - Nov 2021

Responsibilities:

- Designed and maintained networks for clients.
- Maintained hardware performance, network connectivity, and software updates for clients
- Diagnosed issues with critical hardware and software, including handheld computers and station-specific systems.
- Troubleshooted all network connection problems which arose for clients.
- Assisted clients in maintaining optimal connectivity and bandwidth.

Installed and trained new clients on using their networks efficiently and effectively.

TRAINING COURSES AND CONFERENCES

2014
2013
2013
2014

Skills

- Programming Languages: C/C++, C#, VB.net, Java, Python, JavaScript, SQL, PHP, CSS,
- Artificial Intelligence: Expert Systems, Object Detection and POSE Estimation, Machine Learning, Genetic Algorithms
- using Arduino
- using Lego Robots ev3
- **Development tools:** Visual Studio, Android Studio, SQL Developer
- Frameworks: AngularJS, React Native, ASP.Net Core
- Databases: MySQL
- Hardware: Mobile Phones Maintenance, Computer and Laptop maintenance